Chris Godinho

(Cristiano Barboza Godinho)
<u>cristianobgodinho@gmail.com</u> | 416-788-8662 | Mississauga, ON
LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/cristianobgodinho</u> | GitHub: <u>github.com/chris-godinho</u>
Portfolio: <u>chrisgodinho.com</u>

Summary

Full-stack web developer (certified by EdX/University of Toronto) with a background in logistics, finance and theatre. Experience in banking and warehousing, with a strong work ethic and analytical/problem solving skills. Strong ability to design/build web applications, overseeing it at all stages. Often exceeds established goals and works well in a fast-paced environment.

Technical Skills

Software/Platforms: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Render Software languages: JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS

Other: Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, React, GraphQL, Responsive design

Projects

Juggler

https://github.com/chris-godinho/juggler https://juggler-8f9213eba85d.herokuapp.com/

A schedule and task management app with a focus on maintaining a healthy work/life balance.

Core Responsibilities: Front-end, Back-end, Repository management Languages/Technologies used in project: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, React, MongoDB, Mongoose, Apollo Server, GraphQL, AWS S3, Transloadit

Workflow

https://github.com/project3-team3/workflow-app https://shrouded-reef-15269-7fdf3ccd76bb.herokuapp.com/

An office suite featuring highly customizable widgets, as well as text and video chat capabilities.

Core Responsibilities: Front-end, Back-end, Repository management Languages/Technologies used in project: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, CSS Frameworks (Materialize), Node.js, Express.js, React, MongoDB, Mongoose, Apollo Server, GraphQL, Agora.io, Stream, AWS S3, Transloadit

TravIS

https://github.com/UofTTeam2/TravIS https://travis231017-9762a24c277b.herokuapp.com/

A web-based application designed to simplify travel itinerary management for frequent travelers.

Core Responsibilities: Front-end, Back-end Languages/Technologies used in project: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Express,js, Handlebars.js, MySQL, Sequelize, Chart.js

Work Experience

PIT Operator Oct 2022-Dec 2023

RXO, Inc. Mississauga, ON

Load, unload, move and stack product using material handling equipment; Oversee and maintain warehouse inventory using company management systems and implementing control measures, having attention to detail and strict work ethic.

Key Accomplishments:

- Overhauled warehouse inventory procedures and resolved long-standing inconsistencies;
- Obtained perfect accuracy scores (100%) at warehouse routine cycle counts and third party audits.

Warehouse Associate Jan 2022-Oct 2022

XPO Logistics Mississauga, ON

Receive, sort and put away product; Assemble equipment for delivery and assess quality/integrity of product; Provide general warehouse maintenance.

Key Accomplishments:

 Obtained repeated praise and consistently got positive evaluation for strong work ethic and commitment to accuracy and transparency.

Package Handler Nov 2021-Dec 2021

UPS West Concord, ON

Load and unload packages into delivery vehicles and trailers; Sort and stock packages based on company-established criteria.

Table Dealer Dec 2019-Nov 2020

Great Canadian Gaming Corporation Toronto, ON

Ensure the integrity of the game while providing outstanding service to guests in a very fast-paced environment; Apply security measures and keep track of cash/cheque balance; Perform mental math operations repeatedly. Key Accomplishments:

• Obtained consistently positive reviews from supervisors; dealt through long periods of time at crowded tables.

Actor/Director Dec 2005-Nov 2019

Self-Employed Porto Alegre, Brazil/Toronto, ON

Perform for theatre, TV/film and streaming, utilizing memorization and improvisation abilities; Lead/direct cast and crew for theatre performances; Assume production duties, dealing with venue management, service providers and the general public.

Key Accomplishments:

Nominated for awards as actor; Broke statewide attendance record for a single theatre performance.

Education and Training

Full-Stack Coding Boot Camp (Certificate) July 2023-Jan 2024 EdX/University of Toronto Toronto, ON

Acting for Media (Diploma) Jan 2017-Apr 2018 George Brown College Toronto, ON